<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Felipe Ventura]]></title><description><![CDATA[Building community networks]]></description><link>https://fvntr.github.io/fvntr.com/</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 21:18:52 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Notes on Policing the Planet - Why the Policing Crisis Led to Black Lives Matter - Part 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[Notes on Policing the Planet-Why the Policing Crisis Led to Black Lives Matter]]></description><link>https://fvntr.github.io/fvntr.com//posts/policing-the-planet-1-&amp;-2</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://fvntr.github.io/fvntr.com//posts/policing-the-planet-1-&amp;-2</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&quot;draft-notes-on-policing-the-planet---thug-nation-on-state-violence-and-disposability--blacklivesmatter-and-global-visions-of-abolition-an-interview-with-patrisse-cullors&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#draft-notes-on-policing-the-planet---thug-nation-on-state-violence-and-disposability--blacklivesmatter-and-global-visions-of-abolition-an-interview-with-patrisse-cullors&quot; aria-label=&quot;draft notes on policing the planet   thug nation on state violence and disposability  blacklivesmatter and global visions of abolition an interview with patrisse cullors permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[Draft] Notes on Policing the Planet - “Thug Nation: On State Violence and Disposability” &amp;#x26; “#BlackLivesMatter and Global Visions of Abolition: An Interview with Patrisse Cullors”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Thug Nation: On State Violence and Disposability”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professor Kelley begins this essay with the story of Khalief Browder, who was held at Rikers for several years due to his inability to pay for bail after he was accused of stealing the backpack. He laments his suicide shortly after he was released and frames it as the result of the state’s treatment of Black and Brown people as disposable specifically as enshrined through the city’s ‘broken window’s policy’. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As riots and uprising spread in the 60s, police departments began implementitng the same military and surveillance tactics that were developed against guerrilas in Vietnam. They also regarded Black militants, and by extension Black people, as enemy combatants. The essay cites a 1968 report by the Maryland Crime Commission that details the “commodity riots” that are aimed at instigating political violence and recommends investment in military force to quell domestic unrest. The specific term “broken windows” was first discussed in 1982 by George L. Kelling and James Q. Wilson and argued that small infractions led to more serious crimes and that cultural differences were the sources of poverty and inequality. They argued that an approach that policed the most minor of infractions aggressively was seen as a way of correcting the ‘cultural deficiencies of the poor’. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of note is the attention placed to the hardware used by the police in their campaign against Black people as negatively influencing public opinion, not the treatment itself. Parallels are drawn with security forces in Israel and the favela cleansing in Brazil. ‘Broken windows’ is framed as part of a ” global, neoliberal racial regime firmly rooted in the history of settler colonialism”. This is a permanent war that stretches further than any theory of policing or even police departments. The militarized culture in police departments, rooted in settler colonialism, sees all non-White civilians as enemy combatants and advances an array of collective punishment in day-to-day life. Punishment exists outside of the court law. It functions largely in the court of public opinion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kelley focuses now on the linguistic purpose of terms like ‘thug’ and ‘hoodlum’ and the not so apparent systems that support crimizalization of the poor. There is the aforementioned purpose of framing public opion by criminalizing and dehumanizing Black people. This ‘closes off empathy’ for those that may have broken the law in the court of public opinion. The other function is that it masks the violence by the state. If Black people are framed as society’s true source of violence,then the daily violence perpetrated by the state and capital remains hidden.  Racial taxes, in the form of summons and warrants, provide the financial support to keep these systems funded. He describes a &lt;em&gt;racial tax&lt;/em&gt; as “a direct extraction of surplus by the state that produces nothing but discipline and terror and the reproduction of the state—in other words, revenue by &lt;em&gt;primitive accumulation&lt;/em&gt;.” Primitive accumulation is the process in which the ruling class takes possession of wealth and maintains the poor without land or resources to call their own. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#BLACKLIVESMATTER AND GLOBAL VISIONS OF ABOLITION: AN INTERVIEW WITH PATRISSE CULLORS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this interview Patrisse points out that the majority of proposals presented today in anti-police brutality work actually serves to make the state more present in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Notes on Pedagogy of the Oppressed - Part 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[Notes on Chapter 1 of Pedagogy of the Oppressed]]></description><link>https://fvntr.github.io/fvntr.com//posts/pedagogy-of-the-oppressed-chap-1</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://fvntr.github.io/fvntr.com//posts/pedagogy-of-the-oppressed-chap-1</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&quot;draft-notes-on-pedagogy-of-the-oppressed----1-of-4&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#draft-notes-on-pedagogy-of-the-oppressed----1-of-4&quot; aria-label=&quot;draft notes on pedagogy of the oppressed    1 of 4 permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[Draft] Notes on Pedagogy of the Oppressed -  1 of 4&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The justification for a pedagogy of the oppressed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freire frames oppression as a limiting situation that only the oppressed themselves can transform. Dehumanization requires uncompleted beings conscious of their incompleteness. Humanization is the process of overcoming that alienation. A liberatory pedagogy requires oppressed people to recognize the causes of their dehumanization. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also presents a paradox. Oppressed people exist without the freedom to exist authentically while also inhabiting fear of what freedom entails. This is a space free of the oppressor within. The justification for a pedagogy of the oppressed is to facilitate concrete action against oppression through critical awareness of oppression. It is the means of travelling from oppressed Object to liberated Subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two stages of the pedagogy of the oppressed. The first is a commitment to transformation from oppressed Object to liberated Subject. The second stage is the ongoing process of social liberation and creations of a society where permanent liberation becomes an activity of all.  Freire liberations defines as a mode of action (&lt;em&gt;praxis&lt;/em&gt;) and reflection (&lt;em&gt;theory&lt;/em&gt;) of humans in order to transform social order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why do we need a pedagogy of the oppressed? Because everyone deserves not only to be free to exist, they deserve to be more fully human.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The contradiction between the oppressors and the oppressed, and how it is overcome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The duality of the oppressed is one shaped by and existing in oppression and violence. When the oppressed react to the violence and dehumananization imposed by the oppressors, the oppressing class interprets this as violent. As the oppressors dehumanize others and violate their rights, they themselves also become dehumanized. Only the oppressed, through rebellion, can take away the oppressor’s ability to dominate and suppress. This is an act of love that culminates in the dissolution of the oppressed/oppressor dynamic and leads to humans in the process of liberation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oppression and the oppressors&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oppression and the oppressed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liberation: not a gift, not a self-achievement, but a mutual process&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[A Reflection on ‘Property Rights vs Human Rights’]]></title><description><![CDATA[I found myself thinking about property rights recently in relation to the ongoing civil unrest...]]></description><link>https://fvntr.github.io/fvntr.com//posts/property-rights-vs-human-rights</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://fvntr.github.io/fvntr.com//posts/property-rights-vs-human-rights</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-reflection-on-property-rights&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#a-reflection-on-property-rights&quot; aria-label=&quot;a reflection on property rights permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A Reflection on Property Rights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found myself thinking about property rights recently. The uprising occurring nationwide has left storefronts destroyed and the toppling of statues is picking up. The media has, as always, been quick to demonize what is going on and has pointed to antifa, black blocs, and white anarchists as the culprits. Putting aside how that framing manipulates of the struggles of oppressed people,I found myseld looking for a historical reference to property rights as they relate to damage during civil unrest. I found an essay by Lucy Parsons written in 1905 called ‘Property Rights vs Human Rights’. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She provides an analysis of why property rights supersede human rights and how the institutions that uphold it create unnecessary work to support it. The distinction between unnecessary/useless work and useful labor is one that has special relevance today with the societal shifts going on with COVID-19. The terms ‘essential worker’ has become more and more common during this time as a way of describing the workers and the respective industries necessary to keep society running. This shifts have also highlighted how little power these workers have in their workplace and the precarious conditions endured on a daily basis. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure style=&quot;width: 240px&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/media/lucy.png&quot; alt=&quot;Lucy Parsons&quot;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Lucy Parsons&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also interesting that within this discourse the other part of the workforce is not mentioned.  If ‘essential workers’ perform necessary work, what does the rest of the labor force do and what are they called? By omission, they inhabit the space of ‘unessential work’ and the nature of this work is what Lucy Parsons highlighted brilliantly. The ‘unessential workers’ here are the class of workers whose main responsibility is to maintain property rights and the systems that support it. This class of worker are not needed to sustain civilization. The nature of their labor is to protect, uphold, and also benefit from private property and property rights. The value of useful labor performed by essential workers is also extracted to sustain private property and property rights, yet the class of essential workers has little to no share in it. Their labor and wages are extracted through rent across all facets of their lives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Read the full text &lt;a href=&quot;https://theanarchistlibrary.org/library/lucy-e-parsons-property-rights-vs-human-rights&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>